<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>http://nepalkura.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <image>
      <url>http://nepalkura.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://nepalkura.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 16:42:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://nepalkura.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>नीलोत्पलाम्बा गौळान्त कीर्तनानि</title>
      <link>http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/nilotpalamba-kirtanani/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 16:42:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/nilotpalamba-kirtanani/</guid>
      <description>श्री मुत्तुस्वामि दीक्षित विरचित नीलोत्पलाम्बा गौळान्त कीर्तनानि विभक्ति अर्थ कारक प्रथमा ले कर्ता द्वितीया लाई, कन कर्म तृतीया ले, द्वारा, सँग करण चतुर्थी लाई, लागि, निम्ति सम्प्रदान पञ्चमी देखि, बाट अपादान षष्ठी को, का, की, रो, रा, री, नो, ना, नी सम्बन्ध सप्तमी मा, माथि अधिकरण सम्बोधन हे, ए अभिमुखीकरण १ - नीलोत्पलाम्बा जयति रागम् - नारीरीतिगौळ ताळम् - मिश्र चापु पल्लवि नीलोत्पलाम्बा जयति नित्यशुद्धशुभदायिका श्री श्री नील-उत्पल-अम्बा &amp;ndash; देवि नीलोत्पलाम्बा !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waseem Rizvi 26 Verses</title>
      <link>http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/waseem-rizvi-26-verses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 19:58:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/waseem-rizvi-26-verses/</guid>
      <description>Waseem Rizvi used to be Shia Central Waqf Board Chairman. He filed a petition in the Supreme Court appealing to remove 26 verses from the Quran arguing those verses promote terrorism. He recently converted to Hinduism and got a new name Jitendra Narayan Singh Tyagi. As of now, Mr. Tyagi is in Jail for allegedly hurting religious sentiments. Below is the list of those verses with Nepali translation (copied from Quoran Translation to Nepali from हज्रत मिर्जा ताहिर अहमद published by Islam International Publications Limited (2001).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effects Of Anglo-Indian Education</title>
      <link>http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/the-effects-of-anglo-indian-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 16:38:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/the-effects-of-anglo-indian-education/</guid>
      <description>Book - India and Christian Missions Author - Rev. Edward Storrow, of the London Missionary Society, Calcutta Published Date - 1859 URL - https://archive.org/details/indiaandchristi00storgoog In particular, Page 124, Appendix C is highly relevant for us today. Emphasis all mine.
The Hindu sacred writings profess to teach, not only all that it is needful to know about religion, but about science, philosophy, and history, as well. Geography and astronomy are supposed as really to be subjects of inspired authoritative teaching as theology.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
