<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on </title>
    <link>http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
    <image>
      <url>http://nepalkura.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>http://nepalkura.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 22:57:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>नीलोत्पलाम्बा जयति</title>
      <link>http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/nilotpalamba-jayati/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 22:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/nilotpalamba-jayati/</guid>
      <description>श्री मुत्तुस्वामि दीक्षित विरचित रागम् - नारीरीतिगौळ ताळम् - मिश्र चापु पल्लवि नीलोत्पलाम्बा जयति नित्यशुद्धशुभदायिका श्री नील-उत्पल-अम्बा &amp;ndash; जयति &amp;ndash; नित्य &amp;ndash; शुद्ध &amp;ndash; शुभ दायिका श्री &amp;ndash; अनुपल्लवि मूलाज्ञानहरगुरुहजननी फाललोचनी पुराणी पन्नगवेणी नतवाणी मूल-अज्ञान हर &amp;ndash; गुरु गुह जननी &amp;ndash; फाल लोचनी &amp;ndash; पुराणी &amp;ndash; पन्नग वेणी &amp;ndash; नत वाणी &amp;ndash; चरणम् शिवकामेश्वरी शङ्करी शृङ्गाररसकरी पाशाङ्कुशधरी परमदयाकरी भवरोगहरनिपुणवरदायिन्यां नारायणगौळ रागमोदिन्यां भुक्तिमुक्तिमचिच्तं विलयतु शिव काम-ईश्वरी &amp;ndash; शङ्करि &amp;ndash; शृङ्गार रस-करी &amp;ndash; पाश-अङ्कुश धरी &amp;ndash; परम दया-करी &amp;ndash; भव रोग हर निपुण-तर वर दायिन्यां &amp;ndash; नारायण गौळ राग मोदिन्यां &amp;ndash; भुक्ति मुक्ति मद्-चित्तं विलयतु &amp;ndash; &amp;mdash; dikshitar-kriti-neelotpalaambaa-jayathi </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waseem Rizvi 26 Verses</title>
      <link>http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/waseem-rizvi-26-verses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 19:58:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/waseem-rizvi-26-verses/</guid>
      <description>Waseem Rizvi used to be Shia Central Waqf Board Chairman. He filed a petition in the Supreme Court appealing to remove 26 verses from the Quran arguing those verses promote terrorism. He recently converted to Hinduism and got a new name Jitendra Narayan Singh Tyagi. As of now, Mr. Tyagi is in Jail for allegedly hurting religious sentiments. Below is the list of those verses with Nepali translation (copied from Quoran Translation to Nepali from हज्रत मिर्जा ताहिर अहमद published by Islam International Publications Limited (2001).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effects Of Anglo-Indian Education</title>
      <link>http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/the-effects-of-anglo-indian-education/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 16:38:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/the-effects-of-anglo-indian-education/</guid>
      <description>Book - India and Christian Missions Author - Rev. Edward Storrow, of the London Missionary Society, Calcutta Published Date - 1859 URL - https://archive.org/details/indiaandchristi00storgoog In particular, Page 124, Appendix C is highly relevant for us today. Emphasis all mine.
The Hindu sacred writings profess to teach, not only all that it is needful to know about religion, but about science, philosophy, and history, as well. Geography and astronomy are supposed as really to be subjects of inspired authoritative teaching as theology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>कमलाम्बा नवावरणं सार्थम्</title>
      <link>http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/kamalambanavaranam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://nepalkura.github.io/posts/kamalambanavaranam/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents नवावरणध्यानकीर्तनम् १ - प्रथमा विभक्ति नवावरणध्यानकीर्तनम् नवावरणध्यानकीर्तनम् ।। कमलाम्बिके ।। रागं - तोडि रुपक तालम् पल्लवि कमलांबिके आश्रितकल्पलतिके चण्डिके कमनीयारुणांशुके करविधृतशुके मामव जगदंबिके कमलांबिके हे देवी कमलम्बिका (कमल माता) आश्रित - कल्प - लतिके जो कल्पक रूख जस्तै हुनुहुन्छ (जसले सबै वरदानहरू प्रदान गर्दछ) जसले तपाईमा शरण लिन्छन् चण्डिके भयंकर, शक्तिका दस पक्षहरू मध्ये एक कमनीय - अरुण - अंशुके आकर्षक, रातो लुगा लगाएकि कर-विधृते-शुके हातमा सुता समातेको मां मलाई अव रक्षा अनुपल्लवि कमलासनादिपूजितकमलपदे बहुवरदे कमलालयतीर्थवैभवे शिवे करुणार्णवे कमलासन-तीर्थ-पूजित ब्रह्मा र अन्य देवताहरू द्वारा पूजिने कमल-पदे कमलको खुट्टा भएकि बहु-वरदे धेरै वरदानहरू (भक्तहरूलाई) कमलालय-तीर्थ-वैभवे कमलालयलाई महानता प्रदान गर्ने शिवे शुभ मयि करुणा-अर्णवे दयाकि सागर चरणम् सकललोकनायिके संगीतरसिके सुकवित्वप्रदायिके सुन्दरि गतमायिके विकलेबरमुक्तिदाननिपुणे अघहरणे वियदादिभूतकिरणे विनोदचरणे अरुणे सकल-लोक-नायिके सारा संसारको शासक संगीत-रसिके संगीतमा रमाउने सु-कवित्व-प्रदायिके काव्यात्मक प्रतिभाको वरदान दिने सुन्दरि सुन्दरि गत-मायिके जसले भ्रमलाई पार गरेकि वि-कलेश्वर-मुक्ति-दान-निपुणे शरीर बिना मुक्ति प्रदान गर्नमा निपुण (विदेहा मुक्ति) अध-हरणे सबै पापहरू हटाईदिने वियदादि-भूत-किरणे जसले पञ्च तत्वहरू, अन्तरिक्ष, वायु, अग्नि, जल र पृथ्वीलाई मनमोहक चरणहरूद्वारा उत्सर्जन गर्दछ विनोद-चरणे मनमोहक खुट्टा द्वारा अरुणे रातो मध्यमकालसाहित्यम् सकले गुरुगुरुहकरणे सदाशिवान्तःकरणे अ-क-च-ट-त-पादिवर्णे अखण्डैकरसपूर्णे सकले पूर्ण, पूर्ण गुरुगुह-हरणे गुरुगुहाकी माता शदिशिव-अन्तःकरणे भगवान शिवको श्रवण गरी बसोबास गर्ने अ-क-च-ट-त-पादि-वर्णे अ, का, च, ट, त, पा आदि सबै अक्षरहरूको अवतार अखण्ड-एक-रस-पूर्णे अतुलनीय आनन्दले भरिएको १ - प्रथमा विभक्ति कमलांबा संरक्षतु मां रागं आनन्दभैरवि - तिश्र एक तालम् पल्लवि</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
